Preliminary Guide to the Grosvenor Chapman papers, 1931-1994 MS2181
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Grosvenor Chapman papers
1931-1994
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Chapman, Grosvenor
MS2181
25 Linear Feet
This collection contains papers documenting the civic and professional activities of the late Grosvenor Chapman including those as a member of the Committee of 100 on the Federal City and as a local architect. The records date from 1931-1994 with the bulk falling between 1957-1984.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Grosvenor Chapman.
Biographical/Historical note
Grosvenor B. Chapman (1911-1993) was president of the Progressive Citizens Association, president of the Citizens Association of Georgetown and the Georgetown Planning Council and chairman of the Committee of 100. His interests involved planning and preservation in the District, especially in Georgetown. For three decades, Mr. Chapman fought for the preservation of the natural beauty of Potomac Valley gorge by opposing massive freeways, bridges, and high-rise construction in the gorge area and palisades. Chapman helped block the destruction of the historic residential character of Lafayette Square.
Chapman was a partner and founder of the architectural firm Chapman & Miller. He was president of the Washington chapter of the American Institute of Architects and a member of its College Fellows and its Committee on the National Capital.
He was born in Paris to American parents and graduated from Yale School of Fine Arts. His private practice in architecture began in 1940. He served in the Navy during World War II.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains reports, photographs, audio cassettes, correspondence, legal documents, studies, slides, presentations, testimonies, and hearings related to the work of Grosvenor Chapman during his time as a leader in historic preservation in Washington, DC. Much of Chapman's work was related to transportation projects and their impact on the ciy especially projects impacting Georgetown. The materials date from 1931-1994 with the bulk falling between 1957-1984.
Please note: Because the series have been created for ease of browsing and not during processing it is possible that a folder, based solely on folder title, could legitimately fall within two or more series. However, physically a folder may only reside in one series. Therefore, please review the entire finding aid to ensure all appropriate data is discovered.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Collection remains in original order, but folder titles were alphabetized within the finding aid and eleven series were created for ease of browsing the finding aid. These series include: Commissions and hearings, Financial records, Graphics and specifications, Legal documents, Personal papers, Organizations, People, Publicity, Transportation and zoning, Architectural work of Grosvenor Chapman and Recordings.
Transportation -- Washington Metropolitan Area; Georgetown (Washington, D.C.); Interstate 66 (Va. and Washington, D.C.); Georgetown Waterfront (Washington, D.C.); Architecture; Whitehurst Freeway (Washington, D.C.); Urban transportation; Urban renewal; United States. National Capital Planning Commission; Chapman, Grosvenor; Committee of 100 on the Federal City (Washington, D.C.)
- Commissions and hearings, 1962-1990; Series 1
  - Committee on Urban Conservation, 1965; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Urban Conservation handbook on transportation facts, undated; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Conference D.C.Building, 1968 November 27; Series 1 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - D.C. Highways Hearings, 1963-1965; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - D.E.I.S. preliminary [Draft Environmental Impact Statement], 1984; Series 1 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Emergency Committee in the Transportation Crisis, undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Federal City Council Freeways in the National Capital Region, 1966 April; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Fine Arts Commission, 1972-1973; Series 1 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Fine Arts Commission: meeting, 1976 March 10 - 1988 May 24; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fine Arts panel, 1962-1977; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fine Arts panel, 1978-1980; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Freeway Public Hearing, 1969-1975; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Fund raising committee of 100, 1975-1976; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - National Capital Planning Commission forecasting 1985 transportation requirements, 1966 February 26; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - National Capital Planning Commission Freeway plans, undated; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - National Capital Planning Commission mass transportation survey, 1965 Sptember 9; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - National Capital Planning Commission plan for National Capital, 1968 November 15; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Nomination of Alan S. Boyd, 1967 April 26; Series 1 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Planning Coalition D.C. citizens, 1978-1979; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Planning Committee City Planning Coalition, 1979-1980; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Public hearing 73-20-21 C.A.G. testimony, 1973; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 D.C. Depts. testimony, undated; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 Grosvenor Chapman testimony, 1973; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 Grosvenor Chapman testimony, undated; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 NCPC testimony, undated; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 Post-hearing record, 1973; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 Public Witnesses zoning, 1973; Series 1 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Public Hearing 73-20-21 traffic, 1973; Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Public Hearing testimony, 1984; Series 1 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Public Hearing zoning, 1972; Series 1 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Route I-266 Pub Hearings, 1964; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Savanah Historic Preservation, 1968-1969; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Steering Committee meeting minutes, 1982-1984; Series 1 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Symposium on the National Capital Interior, 1979-1980; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Town meeting on canal, 1976 July 17; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Volpe meeting, 1969; Series 1 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Waterfront answers to Interim rezoning petition, 1972; Series 1 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Waterfront: Interim Rezoning Petition, 1972; Series 1 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Whitehurst freeway panel debate, 1990 December 10; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Woodland Hills Residents Association appeal, 1979 March 2; Series 1 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Transportation and zoning, 1966-1990; Series 9
    - 38 K Maintenance of Planting [1 of 2], 1966-1968; Series 9 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - 38 K Maintenance of Planting [2 of 2], 1968-1970; Series 9 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - American Insitiute of Architects D.C. highway analysis, 1968 January 2; Series 9 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Building Products Competition awards and testimonials, 1980-1991; Series 9 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Conviction and Burling zoning, 1973; Series 9 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Freeways I-66, 1973-1976; Series 9 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - D.C. Department of Highways and Traffic I-695, 1972 March; Series 9 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Data for planning, 1979-1981; Series 9 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Documents and correspondence Public hearing zoning, 1973; Series 9 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Draft: River Front Drive An Alternative for the Whitehurst corridor, 1984 September 12; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Draft: Whitehurst Freeway Corridor System Modification Study, 1984 April; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - F Parkway alternative, 1983 February 11; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Feasibility Study Advisory Committee, 1970 November; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Feasibility Study deLaittre File, 1969-1970; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Foggy Bottom tunnel correspondence, 1983; Series 9 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Freeway I-66, 1973; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Freeways I-66 (Peter Craig), 1973; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Freeways I-66 [1 of 2], 1973-1974; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Freeways I-66 [2 of 2], 1974-1977; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Freeways I-66 3 Sisters Bridge, 1972-1978; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Freeways South Leg, 1973-1974; Series 9 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Friendship Heights Case 73-29 73-30 R-5-B text zoning, 1977-1978; Series 9 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - General reference zoning, 1972-1977; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - General zoning, 1978-1979; Series 9 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Geogetown Waterfront, 1966-1969; Series 8 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Grover Chapman: presentations, 1989-1990; Series 9 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - High Rise zoning, 1972-1973; Series 9 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Incinerator, 1985-1988; Series 9 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum: Request Whitehurst Modification Study to be reopened, 1989 March 29; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Montgomery County Council Three Sisters Bridge, undated; Series 9 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - New Orleans, 1976; Series 9 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Presentation Whitehurst corridor study, undated; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Project Program: Military Family Housing Project, 1972; Series 9 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Proposal: An Avenue Alternative to Whitehurst Freeway, 1989 November; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rail transit, 1965; Series 9 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Sectional Development Plan zoning, 1974; Series 9 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Sectional Development Plan zoning amendments, 1973; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Social background of planning, 1973-1974; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Transportation crisis, 1968-1969; Series 9 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Transportation Crisis, 1968-1970; Series 9 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Transportation department of, 1973-1976; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Tunnel Engineers, 1964-1969; Series 9 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Volta Park, 1997; Series 9 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Waterfront [georgetown waterfront], 1968-1973; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Waterfront Rezoning - #3 [georgetown waterfront], 1971-1973; Series 9 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Western Development coproration, undated; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Whitehurst, 1989-1990; Series 9 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Corridor map and blueprints, 1983; Series 9 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Corridor Study report, 1984 February 29; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Corridor System Modification Study [1 or 2], 1985 August; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Corridor System Modification Study [2 of 2], 1985 August; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Phase A, 1983; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Whitehurst Freeway phase B, 1983; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Whitehurst Freeway Resolution correspondence notes, 1990; Series 9 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Whitehurst Freeway: administration names, undated; Series 9 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Writ of Mandamus zoning [1of 2], 1972; Series 9 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Writ of Mandamus zoning [2 of 2], 1972; Series 9 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Zoning Commission order no. 103 and 104, 1974-1975; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Zoning general, 1971-1976; Series 9 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Zoning plans, undated; Series 9 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Financial records, 1953-1983; Series 2
  - A801 sale, 1966; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - A866 Settlement, 1981; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A866 Thomas Bertke, 1981; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bending Lane bank check records, 1971 January - 1973 January; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bending Lane bank check records, 1973 January - 1975 August; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bending Lane bank check records, 1975 August - 1978 August; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Bending Lane bank check records, 1978 August - 1980 December; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1977; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1978; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1979; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1980; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1981; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Bending Lane bank statements, 1971; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bending Lane cash journal general ledger, 1960-1961; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Bending Lane cash journal general ledger 66/68 69/74, 1962-1963; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bending Lane cash journal general ledger BL 65 breakdown, 1959; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Bending Lane financial statements, 1963-1975; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Bending Lane ledger, 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bending Lane: paid bills, 1963-1965; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Committee of 100 Convington-Burling account, 1973; Series 2 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Const A/C bills paid general expense [1 of 3], 1957-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Const A/C bills paid general expense [2 of 3], 1962-1963; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Const A/C bills paid general expense [3 of 3], 1962; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Construction account, 1957; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Construction account cash jounal general ledger jobs 75/76 and 77/78, 1958; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Construction account cash journal ledger, 1956; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Construction accounts, 1953-1955; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Contributions fund campaign, 1976; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Escrow A/C T. McK, 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Escrow interstate acct. transfer fed S&ampL, 1978-1979; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Financial costs: selling prices, 1953-1962; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Fund raising, 1976; Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - General ledger job cost records [1 of 3], 1961; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General ledger job cost records [2 of 3], 1961-1962; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - General ledger job cost records [3 of 3], 1962 January - 1963 January; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - O'brien lease, 1982-1983; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Rent adjustments, 1969-1980; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Transfer of Highway Funds and Freeways, 1975-1976; Series 2 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Graphics and specificiations, 1931-1989; Series 3
  - Architecture notebook, 1931-1932; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Architecture notebook late phases of Mediaeval architecture, 1934; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Architecture Report: Chesapeake Bay Region, 1963; Series 3 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Bending Lane photographs exterior, 1964; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Bending Lane photographs interior, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Brochure duplicates, 1968; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Column drafts, 1971-1972; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Custom designed house 7200 Pyle road, 1952; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Custom designed house Esworthy Road, 1952; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Eastgate presentation drawings, 1968-1989; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Experimental Photos, 1979; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Georgetown Waterfront, undated; Series 3 (Box 51)
    General
    The origin of these images (where they came from and the name of the photographer) is unknown as is the date.
  - Guide to Washington Architecture booklet, 1791-1957; Series 3 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - McGovern House Maine photographs, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - McGovern House photographs proofs, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Negatives, contact sheets: Washington D.C., undated; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Old photographs, undated; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Old Specifications, 1956-1976; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, undated; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs Whitehurst, 1990; Series 3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Photos, undated; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Plans 3335 Q Street, 1949; Series 3 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Plans 3335 Q Street, undated; Series 3 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Post Benj Forgey, 1982 January 23; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Recipts, 1978-1979; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reservoir road draft specifications houses 5-10 BL 69/74, 1961; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Robert Cohen residence, 1951; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Slides: various houses in D.C., undated; Series 3 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Slides: Washington D.C. E-W streests [East to West], undated; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Slides: Washington D.C. N-S streests [North to South], 1979; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Specifications, 1975-1976; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Specifications BL 65 1960, 1978; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Specifications BL 66/68, undated; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Specifications BL(Bending Lane) 66/68, 1960; Series 3 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Specifications highlights, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Sullivan residence photographs, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Sullivan residence photographs exterior, undated; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Vent Hill presentation material, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Waterfront Development Study (architectural drawings), 1972; Series 3 (Box 53)
  - White House, 1972-1973; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Legal documents, 1971-1984; Series 4
  - Attorney fees, 1975; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Brief for Appellant Citizens Association of Georgetown, 1972 December 4; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Civil Action "exparte", 1975-1978; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Congress, undated; Series 4 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Contract 4801, 1977-1978; Series 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Court of Appeals, 1973 February 6; Series 4 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Land Use theory, 1974-1975; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Law policy statements Waterfront, 1971-1972; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Law case zoning, 1975; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Law cases zoning, 1972-1975; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Law Suit injunction, 1977; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Legal accounts and correspondence, 1974-1979; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Legal correspondence with attorney, 1975-1978; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Legal depositions Air quality suit, 1973; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Legal pretrial, 1974 June 10; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Legal trial, 1974 June 10; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Legislation, 1973; Series 4 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Miller (E.T.) Resolution, 1971-1981; Series 4 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Reasons U.S. Court of Appeals, 1973 May; Series 4 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Reply brief for Appellant Committee of 100 on the Federal City, 1972 December 19; Series 4 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Resolution, 1984 April 9; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Resolution accepting 2.4 m.s.f. and correspondence, 1975; Series 4 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Robert Levine case, 1980; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Waterfront extra resolutions, 1971; Series 4 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Personal records, 1957-1990; Series 5
  - Architecture criticism, undated; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Barry administration, 1979-1980; Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Biography, 1957-1992; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Chronology, 1971-1975; Series 5 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1979; Series 5 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1976; Series 5 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence by others re: Waterfront, 1972-1975; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cosmos Club Admission Chapman biography, 1953-1960; Series 5 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Developers, 1968; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Development Rights transfer, 1966-1971; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Directory of Historic Preservation in the District of Columbia, 1972 April; Series 5 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Dodge Center, undated; Series 5 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Elections, 1989-1990; Series 5 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Fire 4801, 1977; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Georgetown Waterfront Personal Professional, 1970-1971; Series 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inland, 1971-1974; Series 5 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Inland Steel beginning, 1975; Series 5 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Letters of thanks, undated; Series 5 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous permanent records, 1955-1967; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Trust, 1973; Series 5 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Next column, undated; Series 5 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Opposition, 1973; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Plaque [photocopy of], undated; Series 5 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Separated Materials
    The original plaque was removed from the collection. The photocopy of the plaque found in this file provides the visual data found on the original.
  - Politics national, 1988-1989; Series 5 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Population, 1969-1976; Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Racial inuendos, 1973 October 15; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reading file Mr. Chapman, 1975-1976; Series 5 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - University of Virginia seminar, undated; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Useful information, 1982; Series 5 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Organizations, 1956-1994; Series 6
  - A.I.A. fellowship [American Institute of Architects], 1965-1966; Series 6 (Box 13, Folder Folder 5)
  - A.I.A. Highway Study December 1967 for D.C. Council [American Institute of Architects], 1967-1970; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 8)
  - A.I.A. Mass Transit [American Institute of Architects], 1956; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 7)
  - A.I.A. Program Committee Dinner [American Institute of Architects], 1956 January 10; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 6)
  - A.I.A. Washington Metropolitan Chapter [American Institute of Architects], 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 5)
  - A.N.C. cmprehensive plan [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 11)
  - A.N.C. correspondence [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1977 June; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 5)
  - A.N.C. election [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 2)
  - A.N.C. election [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1978; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 3)
  - A.N.C. minutes [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976-1977; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 4)
  - A.N.C. planning M.P.O. goals [Municipal Planning Office and Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1977; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 17)
  - A.N.C. planning zoning and developing [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1977; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 10)
  - A.N.C. planning zoning and housing [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], undated; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 9)
  - A.N.C. plans: Fine Arts Committee [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976-1977; Series 6 (Box 3, Folder Folder 10)
  - A.N.C. pollution air and water [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 2)
  - A.N.C. press [Advisory Neighborhood Commissions], 1976-1977; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder Folder 8)
  - Ad hoc Whitehurst Freeway group, 1984; Series 6 (Box 33, Folder Folder 11)
  - Advisory Committee on the Waterfont Feasibility Study, 1970-1971; Series 6 (Box 17, Folder Folder 4)
  - Appeal D.B.C., 1977; Series 6 (Box 21, Folder Folder 11)
  - B.P.A.G., 1984-1990; Series 6 (Box 33, Folder Folder 5)
  - Reports to C.A.G. [Citizens Association of Georgetown], 1975-1976; Series 6 (Box 5, Folder Folder 4)
  - C.A.G Bicentennial [Citizens Association of Georgetown], undated; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder Folder 4)
  - C.A.G. G.P.C.: Collaboration [Citizens Association of Georgetown, Georgetown Presbyterian Church], undated; Series 6 (Box 18, Folder Folder 4)
  - Appeal C.A.G. [Citizens Association of Georgetown], 1978; Series 6 (Box 21, Folder Folder 12)
  - C.A.G. 1220 Wisc [Citizens Association of Georgetown], 1979-1980; Series 6 (Box 1, Folder Folder 10)